【The fate that cannot be liberated】
[해방될 수 없는 운명]
[Episode 14]
[14화]
Still unhappy?
아직도 불행해요?
How would you be happy?
어떻게 행복할까요?
You don't understand anything.
당신은 아무것도 이해하지 못합니다.
I am oblivious.
나는 잊어 버렸다.
I know.
알아요.
If he knew, why did he do so many things?
만약 알았다면 왜 그렇게 많은 일을 했을까요?
Stupid, trivial.
어리석고 하찮은 일이다.
Something that worries you?
당신을 걱정하는 것이 있습니까?
You could die if you fell into the lake.
호수에 빠지면 죽을 수도 있어요.
Do you know what death means?
죽음이 무엇을 의미하는지 아시나요?
My whole family died.
우리 가족 모두가 죽었습니다.
I have nothing now.
나는 지금 아무것도 없습니다.
But you have so much.
하지만 당신은 너무 많은 것을 가지고 있습니다.
And he did a lot of stupid things.
그리고 그는 어리석은 짓을 많이 했습니다.
forget.
잊다.
Let's stop arguing. Meaningless.
논쟁을 멈추자. 무의미한.
I want to find your deceased relatives and return them to you,
돌아가신 친척을 찾아 돌려드리고 싶습니다 .
But I can't.
하지만 난 할 수 없습니다.
I have no idea
나는 전혀 모른다
It is going to fall into the lake today.
오늘은 호수에 빠질 예정이에요.
You will hate it.
당신은 그것을 싫어할 것입니다.
I just want her to be happier.
나는 단지 그녀가 더 행복해지기를 바랄 뿐입니다.
Look, lady.
보세요, 아가씨.
This is General He Liang created for you.
이것은 당신을 위해 창조된 허량 장군입니다.
Do you think this is ridiculous?
이것이 말도 안된다고 생각하십니까?
I agree.
나는 동의한다.
Everyone thinks he is stupid.
모두가 그가 바보라고 생각합니다.
and innocence.
그리고 결백.
But he's the only one
하지만 그 사람은 유일한 사람이야
will do these things.
이런 일들을 할 것입니다.
The young master tried his best to
젊은 주인은 최선을 다해 노력했다.
Make you happy.
너를 행복하게 만든다.
He wants to bring the He family to you,
그는 He 가족을 당신에게 데려오고 싶어합니다.
At least on your birthday.
적어도 생일에는요.
He wants you to take your family with you.
그는 당신이 가족을 데리고 가기를 원합니다 .
Your father is a general, right?
네 아버지는 장군이시지?
He must have been a very authoritarian man.
그는 매우 권위주의적인 사람이었을 것입니다.
this.
이것.
This is your brother.
이 사람은 당신의 형제입니다.
He is...he is...
그 사람은...그 사람은...
My brother is a...
내 동생은 ...
Strategist.
전략가.
This is a book I wrote before.
이 책은 제가 예전에 썼던 책입니다.
I gave it to him.
나는 그에게 그것을 주었다.
This is your second brother.
이 사람은 당신의 둘째 동생이에요.
The second brother is a major general.
둘째 형은 소장이다.
He is as powerful as his father.
그는 그의 아버지만큼 강력합니다.
This is the third brother.
이것은 셋째 형제입니다.
Third brother...
셋째 형...
I haven't dressed him yet.
나는 아직 그에게 옷을 입히지 않았습니다.
You woke up too early.
당신은 너무 일찍 일어났습니다.
is crying.
울고있다.
To be honest, there's nothing I can do.
솔직히 말해서 제가 할 수 있는 일은 아무것도 없습니다.
No, Rong Yu.
아니, 유롱.
The rabbit and fish he gave me
그가 준 토끼와 물고기
They are very important to my family.
그들은 우리 가족에게 매우 중요합니다.
I like them very much.
나는 그들을 매우 좋아합니다.
and even?
그리고 심지어?
So on your birthday,
그러니까 생일날,
I will bring you rabbits, fish and family.
토끼, 물고기, 가족을 데려오겠습니다 .
A small rabbit is enough.
작은 토끼 한 마리면 충분합니다.
Don't build so many snowmen.
눈사람을 너무 많이 만들지 마세요.
You need to take care of yourself.
당신은 자신을 돌봐야합니다.
I'm not cold.
나는 춥지 않다.
But you will be happy when your family is around
하지만 가족이 곁에 있으면 행복할 거예요
Celebrate your birthday.
생일을 축하하세요.
You are also part of my family.
당신은 또한 나의 가족의 일부입니다.
Do not do?
하지 마세요?
Per year,
연간,
If you follow
팔로우하면
your rabbit,
너의 토끼,
She will be happy.
그녀는 행복할 것이다.
I want to stay with my rabbit.
나는 토끼와 함께 있고 싶다.
Ling.
링.
Don't cry.
울지 마세요.
I hope that in the days to come,
앞으로의 날에는
You should be happy every day.
당신은 매일 행복해야합니다.
good girl.
착한 여자 아이.
You must be very happy.
당신은 매우 행복해야합니다.
group.
그룹.
Chenzhou.
천저우.
Qingxing.
칭싱.
Qiuting.
큐팅.
Pai, Chenzhou, Qingxing.
파이, 천저우, 칭싱.
If you never treat someone sincerely,
누군가를 진심으로 대하지 않는다면,
you will never suffer a loss
당신은 결코 손실을 입지 않을 것입니다
or separation.
또는 이별.
But with this person,
그런데 이 사람이랑은
I want to try it one last time.
마지막으로 한번 해보고 싶습니다.
Longevity noodles are here.
장수국수가 나왔습니다.
Madam, although the young master did not do it,
부인, 젊은 스승은 그렇게 하지 않았지만,
was done
끝났다
under his supervision.
그의 감독하에.
So it can be considered a family relationship.
따라서 가족관계라고 볼 수 있습니다.
Miss. listen.
놓치다. 듣다.
if i didn't stop
내가 멈추지 않았다면
He wants to do it himself.
그는 그 일을 스스로 하고 싶어합니다.
So, you can't
그래서 당신은 할 수 없습니다
Eat longevity noodles in the morning.
아침에는 장수국수를 먹어보세요.
Thanks.
감사해요.
let me try
나 해보자
The longevity noodles you prepared.
당신이 준비한 장수국수.
delicious. This is the best I've ever had.
맛있는. 이것은 내가 먹어본 것 중 최고입니다.
How are your hands?
손은 어때요?
Yes, thank you my husband.
네, 고마워요 남편.
husband.
남편.
That's what you called me.
당신이 나를 그렇게 불렀어요.
Why?
왜?
Can't I?
나는 할 수 없습니까?
No.
아니요.
i can make a small
내가 작게 만들 수 있어
Terrace pharmacy?
테라스 약국?
I lost everything in Nanjiang.
나는 난장에서 모든 것을 잃었습니다.
I now have to raise insects.
이제 곤충을 키워야 해요.
But there are also some strangers.
하지만 낯선 사람도 있습니다.
no problem?
괜찮아요?
Furthermore, if I
게다가 만약 내가
Please eat them,
꼭 먹어주세요,
Will you eat them?
먹을 건가요?
But this will be our secret.
하지만 이것은 우리의 비밀이 될 것입니다.
In addition to flattening,
평탄화 외에도,
Even Lord Rong doesn’t know, do you understand?
롱 경도 모르잖아요, 알겠어요?
Why did you just accept it?
왜 그냥 받아들였나요?
Don't have anything to ask?
물어볼 게 없나요?
you can
당신은 할 수
Do you call me that husband again?
또 나를 그 남편이라고 부르나요?
husband.
남편.
Do you want one?
하나 원하시나요?
Warm.
따뜻한.
Thanks.
감사해요.
slowly.
느리게.
This is good?
이거 좋은데?
[Weiyang.]
[웨이양.]
- It's beautiful, isn't it? - Grace.
- 정말 아름답지 않나요? - 우아함.
Sim.
심.
group.
그룹.
Chenzhou, sister.
천저우 언니.
Qingxing e Ying.
칭싱과 잉.
Qiuting.
큐팅.
New Year is coming. Happy New Year.
새해가 다가오고 있습니다. 새해 복 많이 받으세요.
Here, sir.
여기요, 선생님.
- He's arrived. - Thanks.
- 도착했어요. - 감사해요.
【Rongfu】
【롱푸】
please enter.
들어 오세요.
This is the great master
이것이 바로 위대한 스승이다
I told you.
내가 말했잖아.
He is also famous in Xijiang.
그는 Xijiang에서도 유명합니다.
I understand the situation.
상황을 이해합니다.
On the way to the capital,
수도로 가는 길에,
I also thought of some solutions.
나는 또한 몇 가지 해결책을 생각했습니다.
However, seeing Mr. Rong’s clear eyes,
그러나 롱 씨의 맑은 눈을 보면
His behavior is no different from ordinary people.
그의 행동은 보통 사람들과 다르지 않습니다.
Based on the current health status,
현재 건강상태를 토대로
Xijiang still needs to use our methods
Xijiang은 여전히 ​​우리의 방법을 사용해야 합니다
Thorough investigation
철저한 조사
Before we draw conclusions.
결론을 내리기 전에.
random.
무작위의.
But I have rules.
하지만 나에겐 규칙이 있다.
There can be no more interruptions.
더 이상 방해가 될 수 없습니다.
Mr. Rong, could you please step aside?
롱씨, 비켜주실 수 있나요?
Understood. Thank you for your help, Master.
이해했다. 도와주셔서 감사합니다, 마스터.
I know.
알아요.
This is an echo bug.
이것은 에코 버그입니다.
Do you know this insect?
이 곤충을 아시나요?
But it should be gold.
하지만 금이어야 합니다.
How do you know there is gold?
금이 있다는 것을 어떻게 알 수 있나요?
Isn't this very common?
이런 일은 흔한 일이 아닌가?
impossible.
불가능한.
Echo errors are rare,
에코 오류는 거의 발생하지 않습니다.
The more golden.
더 황금색입니다.
It is difficult to create one ten thousandth.
만분의 일을 만드는 것은 어렵습니다.
and even?
그리고 심지어?
This looks familiar to me.
이것은 나에게 친숙해 보입니다.
These are just regular knives.
이건 그냥 일반 칼이에요.
To use an insect for investigation, I need to draw its blood.
곤충을 조사에 사용하려면 혈액을 채취해야 합니다.
But I wouldn’t take too much.
그러나 나는 너무 많이 받아들이지 않을 것입니다.
no need. Hold it in your hand,
필요 없음. 손에 쥐고,
He would discover the disease on his own.
그는 스스로 질병을 발견할 것입니다.
No, not my melon.
아니, 내 멜론은 아니야.
No.
아니요.
What is Guagua?
과과(Guagua)란 무엇입니까?
Who said he was stupid?
누가 그가 바보라고 말했습니까?
He is definitely an expert in medicine.
그는 확실히 의학의 전문가입니다.
Master, have you raised any insect pests?
마스터님 혹시 해충 키워보신적 있으신가요?
What insect?
무슨 곤충?
Tell me and I can get someone to help you find them.
저에게 말씀해 주시면 찾는 데 도움을 줄 수 있는 사람을 불러올 수 있습니다.
Does he have so many bugs that he can’t even remember them?
버그가 너무 많아서 기억도 못하는 걸까요?
How about I buy my bugs?
내 벌레를 사는 게 어때요?
Clear. It will be good.
분명한. 괜찮을 꺼야.
Are you a disciple of Xuantian Hermit?
당신은 Xuantian Hermit의 제자입니까?
Is this just a coincidence?
이것은 단지 우연일까요?
Don't panic.
당황하지 말 것.
I must be thinking too much.
내가 너무 많은 생각을 하고 있는 게 틀림없다.
I helped him up.
나는 그를 도와주었다.
as you know
아시다시피
How to create a top-notch insect?
최고의 곤충을 만드는 방법은 무엇입니까?
It's easy.
그것은 간단합니다.
simple?
단순한?
May I ask, Master?
물어봐도 될까요, 선생님?
Who is your master?
당신의 주인은 누구입니까?
let me guess.
어디 보자.
I heard that in the past,
예전에 그런 말을 들었는데,
Xuantian hermit has a certain relationship
Xuantian 은둔자는 특정 관계가 있습니다
and Astrology.
그리고 점성술.
Who are you...
누구세요...
You must be her disciple.
당신은 그녀의 제자가 되어야 합니다.
If you want to punish me in the name of your master
주인의 이름으로 나를 벌하고 싶다면
Why beat around the bush?
왜 덤불 주위를 두드리는가?
You poisoned me.
당신은 나를 독살했습니다.
What poison did you use?
무슨 독을 썼나요?
my whole body
내 온 몸
I felt like I was on fire and couldn't breathe.
불이 붙은 것 같았고 숨을 쉴 수 없었습니다.
he's good. So this was your plan all along?
그는 좋아. 그럼 이것이 당신의 계획이었나요?
It turns out that her apprentice
그녀의 견습생이 밝혀졌습니다.
Even more powerful than herself.
자신보다 훨씬 더 강력합니다.
teacher.
선생님.
Master, I stole her secret book
선생님, 제가 그 사람의 비밀책을 훔쳤어요
and her instrument.
그리고 그녀의 악기.
i learned something
나는 뭔가를 배웠다
And lied about being better than his master,
그리고 자기 주인보다 낫다고 거짓말을 했고,
But I didn't hurt anyone.
하지만 나는 누구에게도 해를 끼치 지 않았습니다.
Please remove the poison from my body.
내 몸의 독을 제거해주세요.
I can't take it anymore.
더 이상 참을 수 없습니다.
I can't stand it.
나는 그것을 참을 수 없다.
Hot, hot, I'm burning.
더워, 더워, 불타오르고 있어.
gentlemen. gentlemen.
신사. 신사.
People from Xijiang jumped into the lake.
시장(Xijiang) 사람들이 호수에 뛰어들었습니다.
What?
무엇?
He jumped into the lake.
그는 호수에 뛰어들었습니다.
What is it doing here?
여기서는 무엇을 하고 있나요?
Aphrodisiac bait.
최음제 미끼.
Why so much less?
왜 그렇게 적은가요?
say. what are they doing?
말하다. 그들은 무엇을 하고 있나요?
What do you mean by "ready"?
"준비"란 무엇을 의미합니까?
when i'm not in the room
내가 방에 없을 때
Did you take my stuff?
내 물건 가져갔어?
It looks like he'll say yes. Rong Yu,
그가 그렇다고 대답할 것 같습니다. 유 롱,
very good!
매우 좋은!
You dare to touch my things without my permission.
감히 내 허락도 없이 내 물건에 손을 대다니.
I'll place an order now.
지금 주문하겠습니다.
Clear.
분명한.
Can you come and live with me again?
다시 와서 나랑 같이 살 수 있나요?
I can sleep outside.
밖에서 잘 수 있어요.
No.
아니요.
I know in other families,
제가 아는 다른 가족들 중에는
The wife and husband share a room.
아내와 남편이 방을 공유합니다.
Moreover, in the inn, you said
게다가 여관에서는 네가 말했지
Married couples can live together.
부부는 함께 살 수 있습니다.
You have a lot of knowledge, right?
지식이 많으시죠?
Why don't you be more determined?
좀 더 결심해 보는 게 어때?
And asked to sleep with me?
그리고 나랑 자자고 했어?
Would you agree?
동의하시겠습니까?
So lacking in confidence?
그래서 자신감이 부족하다?
Then I'll leave...
그럼 난 떠날게...
No.
아니요.
You have to let me sleep today.
오늘은 나 좀 자게 해줘야 해.
Sorry, the time is wrong.
죄송합니다. 시간이 잘못되었습니다.
No.
아니요.
I want to sleep.
나는 자고 싶다.
This is not "putting you to sleep".
이것은 "당신을 잠들게 하는 것"이 ​​아닙니다.
This is "sleeping with you".
이것은 "너와 함께 자다"입니다.
You can sleep with me tomorrow too.
내일도 나랑 자면 돼.
How about the day after tomorrow?
모레는 어떻습니까?
Same thing.
같은 것.
- what is that? - stop. Rong Yu,
- 저게 뭐에요? - 멈추다. 유 롱,
nothing.
아무것도 아님.
Rong Yu, it’s nothing.
유 롱, 아무것도 아니야.
I let it go.
나는 그것을 놔두었다.
Don't pull on my clothes.
내 옷을 잡아당기지 마세요.
I will be angry.
나는 화를 낼 것이다.
Did he take advantage of me not to hit you?
그 사람이 당신을 때리지 않으려고 나를 이용했나요?
But then...
하지만...
No, I'm fine.
아냐 난 괜찮아.
Let me change it first.
먼저 바꿔보겠습니다.
Warm the bed.
침대를 따뜻하게 해주세요.
I feel warm when I go back to sleep.
다시 잠에 들면 따뜻해지는 느낌이 듭니다.
Rong Yu, you were my biggest pain,
Rong Yu, 당신은 나의 가장 큰 고통이었습니다.
but now
그러나 지금
You are my greatest luck.
당신은 나의 가장 큰 행운입니다.
excuse me.
실례합니다.
Lucky money.
행운의 돈.
What is this for?
이것은 무엇을 위한 것입니까?
new year...
새해...
Lucky money.
행운의 돈.
But it was once a gourd.
그러나 그것은 한때 조롱박이었습니다.
Why have you turned into a rabbit again now?
왜 지금은 또 토끼로 변한 걸까요?
What a blessing for me.
나에게는 얼마나 큰 축복인가.
this means...
이것은 의미합니다 ...
There is a lot of money. a lot of money.
돈이 많다. 많은 돈.
I don't want to get rich.
나는 부자가 되고 싶지 않아요.
I just want you.
난 그냥 당신을 원해요.
Your Majesty, the regent is here.
폐하, 섭정이 왔습니다.
Tio.
티오.
Long live the emperor.
황제 만세.
stand up.
일어서세요.
I've said it before, we are a family,
아까도 말했지만, 우리는 가족이에요.
We don't need formalities.
우리는 형식적인 것이 필요하지 않습니다.
Your Majesty, ancestral rites cannot be abolished.
대왕이여, 제사를 폐지할 수 없습니다.
court officials are coming to celebrate the New Year.
폐하, 법원 관계자들이 새해를 축하하기 위해 왔습니다.
You can't stay here.
당신은 여기에 머물 수 없습니다.
I'll stay where you say I should be.
나는 당신이 있어야 한다고 말한 곳에 머물겠습니다.
Your Majesty, you should be present.
폐하, 참석하셔야 합니다.
Why didn't my cousin come today?
오늘 내 사촌은 왜 안 왔나요?
Your Majesty, I ground you today.
폐하, 오늘은 당신을 접지했습니다.
Why?
왜?
state...
상태...
I'm not a stranger.
나는 낯선 사람이 아닙니다.
What doesn't uncle want to tell me?
삼촌이 나에게 말하고 싶어하지 않는 것은 무엇입니까?
Tell me, man.
말해봐, 친구.
Your Majesty,
폐하,
The pine forest is becoming more and more rebellious.
소나무 숲은 점점 더 반항적이 되어가고 있습니다.
She said she was getting married in the spring
봄에 결혼한다고 하더군요
She is also worried that her husband's family will not like her.
그녀는 또한 남편의 가족이 자신을 좋아하지 않을까 걱정합니다 .
She asked me to beg Your Majesty
그녀는 나에게 폐하께 간청해 달라고 부탁했습니다
And granted her the title of princess.
그리고 그녀에게 공주라는 칭호를 부여했습니다.
But how is this possible?
그런데 이것이 어떻게 가능합니까?
I agree.
나는 동의한다.
If it would make my cousin happy.
그것이 내 사촌을 행복하게 해준다면.
Why is it impossible?
왜 불가능합니까?
Wang Dequan, how to write an imperial edict?
왕덕전(王德泉), 황실칙령을 어떻게 쓰나요?
no precedent
전례가 없다
I want to ask Mr. Li
리 선생님께 묻고 싶습니다.
Affiliated to the Ministry of Rites.
예식부 소속.
Do this as soon as possible.
가능한 한 빨리 이 작업을 수행하십시오.
I won't delve into such an irrelevant topic.
그런 쓸데없는 주제는 다루지 않겠습니다 .
Sim.
심.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
감사합니다, 폐하.
Happy New Year to Your Majesty .
폐하께 새해 복 많이 받으세요 .
May all your Majesty go well next year.
폐하께서 내년에도 잘 지내시기를 바랍니다.
I wish Jialin all the best next year.
Jialin이 내년에도 좋은 일만 있기를 바랍니다.
Husband, let it go.
남편, 놔두세요.
On New Year's Eve, important ministers and their families will enter the palace
설날에는 주요 대신들 과 그 가족들이 궁궐에 들어갑니다.
No private guards or weapons.
개인 경비원이나 무기는 없습니다.
If someone wants to kidnap or kill someone
누군가가 누군가를 납치하거나 죽이려고 한다면
This is perfect timing.
이것은 완벽한 타이밍입니다.
Who wants to break up my family?
누가 내 가족을 깨뜨리고 싶나요?
Who framed my family?
누가 내 가족을 모함했나요?
How many people are involved?
몇 명의 사람이 참여하고 있는지?
Today I will discover the truth.
오늘 나는 진실을 발견할 것이다.
Jiuling.
지울링.
Lord Rong. Lord Song.
롱공, 송공.
Jiuling,
지울링,
Are you still cold?
아직도 춥나요?
Why did it take so long?
왜 그렇게 오래 걸렸나요?
Why are you still standing there? Coming soon.
왜 아직도 거기 서 있나요? 곧 출시됩니다.
He is becoming more and more rebellious.
그는 점점 더 반항적이 되어가고 있습니다.
When we worship the Queen Mother,
우리가 태후 어머니를 숭배할 때,
I want them to be polite, okay?
난 그들이 예의바르게 행동하길 바라요, 그렇죠?
Lord Honor.
존경하는 주님.
Happy New Year, Your Majesty.
새해 복 많이 받으세요, 폐하.
Happy New Year.
새해 복 많이 받으세요.
It's hot?
그것은 뜨겁다?
- I'm fine. - sorry.
- 잘 지내요. - 죄송합니다.
I don't understand how amazing this is.
나는 이것이 얼마나 놀라운 일인지 이해하지 못합니다.
Why not straighten the steering wheel?
왜 운전대를 곧게 펴지 않습니까?
- Is a glass of water firm? - it's all my fault.
- 물 한잔은 단단합니까? - 그것은 모두 내 잘못이야.
it's all my fault.
그것은 모두 내 잘못이야.
Master.
주인.
everything is fine.
모든 것이 괜찮습니다.
Because the clothes are all wet
옷이 다 젖으니까
go home.
집에가.
Why don't you ask your servant to give Mrs. Rong a new set of clothes?
당신의 하인에게 롱 부인에게 새 옷 한 벌을 달라고 부탁하는 것이 어때요 ?
Master, no need.
선생님, 필요없습니다.
Don't worry, Master.
걱정하지 마세요, 선생님.
Don't let me delay your majesty
폐하를 지연시키지 마십시오
Neither have you gentlemen here.
여기에는 여러분도 없습니다.
let's go.
갑시다.
Rong Yu.
유 롱.
Mr. Rong.
롱 씨.
Let’s talk to His Majesty first.
먼저 폐하께 말씀드리죠.
I'll wait for you at home.
집에서 기다릴게요.
- I... - Look what Her Majesty is wearing.
- 저는... - 폐하께서 입고 계신 옷을 보세요.
Tell me what he said when he got home.
그가 집에 왔을 때 무슨 말을 했는지 말해주세요 .
Listen to your uncle.
삼촌의 말을 들어보세요.
Sla. Glory.
슬라. 영광.
Madam Rong, the princess wants to see you.
롱 부인, 공주님이 당신을 만나고 싶어합니다.
Your Highness?
전하?
Is Your Highness here?
전하께서 여기 계시나요?
Sim.
심.
Mrs. Rong, please wait here for a moment.
롱 부인, 여기서 잠시만 기다려주세요.
His Highness will arrive soon.
전하께서 곧 도착하실 것입니다.
Tell me, who told you to lie to me?
말해봐, 누가 나한테 거짓말하라고 했어?
To the princess?
공주에게?
This is a lie. I don't know your highness.
이것은 거짓말입니다. 저는 당신의 신분을 모릅니다.
Why did she suddenly drop hints to me?
그녀는 왜 갑자기 나에게 힌트를 준 걸까?
Besides, no one has lived here for a long time.
게다가 여기에 오랫동안 살았던 사람은 아무도 없습니다.
It was obvious that I was attracted to it on purpose.
일부러 끌린 게 분명했다.
I feel like the person who poured water on me
나한테 물 뿌린 사람이 된 기분이야
This is part of your plan, right?
이건 당신 계획의 일부죠?
Tell me, what's going on?
말해봐, 무슨 일이야?
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
it's me.
나야.
In those years, when my father was ill,
그 시절, 아버지가 아팠을 때,
He leaned heavily on the Star Pavilion.
그는 스타 파빌리온에 크게 기대어 있었다 .
He listened to everything Jiang Rong said.
그는 Jiang Rong이 말하는 모든 것을 들었습니다.
and do His will.
그리고 그분의 뜻을 행하십시오.
He started the construction project
그는 건설 프로젝트를 시작했다
and build an astrology studio.
점성술 스튜디오를 지으세요.
He recruited the best psychics in the world.
그는 세계 최고의 심령술사를 모집했습니다.
Jiang Rong can do almost anything.
Jiang Rong은 거의 모든 것을 할 수 있습니다.
After my father passed away,
아버지가 돌아가신 후,
I thought about avoiding the Rong family.
나는 롱 가족을 피하려고 생각했습니다.
But the court hall was surrounded by tigers and wolves.
그러나 법정은 호랑이와 늑대로 둘러싸여 있었습니다.
After the Rong family, there is the Jiang family.
롱(Rong) 가문 다음에는 장(Jiang) 가문이 있다.
Although Lord Zhongyong is my uncle,
중용공은 나의 삼촌이지만
He took advantage of my youth.
그는 내 젊음을 이용했습니다.
Hoje, Jialin
호제, 지알린
It almost became his.
그것은 거의 그의 것이 되었습니다.
Military power and the army were under his control.
군사력 과 군대가 그의 통제하에 있었다.
And their groups
그리고 그들의 그룹
He wanted to destroy the He family by any means necessary.
그는 필요한 모든 수단을 동원하여 He 가족을 파괴하고 싶었습니다.
In the name of the emperor,
황제의 이름으로,
But I had no say in anything.
그러나 나는 아무 말도 하지 않았습니다.
I even had to pretend to be stupid, crazy, and afraid of him.
나는 그를 멍청하고 미친 척하고 두려워하는 척까지 해야 했습니다 .
As they say, when you don't have lips, your teeth get cold.
입술이 없으면 이가 시린다고 합니다.
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
I failed to protect the He family.
나는 He 가족을 보호하지 못했습니다.
That's my fault.
내 탓이야.
Your Majesty.
폐하.
I am guilty, but there is no way I can atone for my sin.
나는 죄가 있지만, 내 죄를 속죄할 수 있는 방법은 없습니다.
Even this label,
이 라벨에도
I'm afraid to let anyone know.
누구에게도 알리기가 두렵습니다.
I play a poor emperor.
나는 가난한 황제를 연기합니다.
I'm that poor man
나는 그 가난한 사람이다
I can't protect my family.
나는 내 가족을 보호할 수 없습니다.
What does it matter?
그것은 무슨 상관이야?
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
When my father was alive,
아버지가 살아 계실 때,
He talked about you.
그는 당신에 대해 이야기했습니다.
The message is that you are better than your teacher.
메시지는 당신 이 선생님보다 낫다는 것입니다.
Em Nanjiang,
엠 난장(Em Nanjiang),
More famous than General He.
허 장군보다 더 유명해요.
if i wasn't a woman
내가 여자가 아니었다면
I will be a general now.
나는 이제 장군이 될 것이다.
Even if this is true,
이것이 사실이라고 하더라도,
it's useless.
그건 소용 없어.
It is not.
그렇지 않습니다.
i want you sir
나는 당신을 원해요 선생님
Be my General He.
나의 장군이 되십시오.
Your Majesty.
폐하.
Throughout history,
역사를 통틀어,
No woman had ever helped the emperor.
어떤 여자도 황제를 도와준 적이 없습니다.
But this great palace
하지만 이 큰 궁전은
It is full of truth and fantasy.
그것은 진실과 환상으로 가득 차 있습니다.
Although I am in a high mood every day,
매일 기분이 좋아도
I have no one I can trust.
나는 믿을 수 있는 사람이 아무도 없습니다.
Think about it carefully,
잘 생각해보세요,
No one believed me either.
아무도 내 말을 믿지 않았습니다.
I got it now
이제 알겠습니다
Conspired with Zhong Yongjun to frame the He family.
종용준과 공모하여 허씨 가문을 모함함.
As for the other messy officers,
다른 지저분한 장교들에 관해서는
I need you to help me investigate them one by one.
하나씩 조사할 수 있도록 도와주세요 .
You need to avenge your family
가족의 복수를 해야 한다
I have national responsibilities.
나에게는 국가적 책임이 있습니다.
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
Can I trust Jialin's future?
Jialin의 미래를 믿을 수 있습니까?
for you?
당신을 위한?
European Union...
유럽 ​​연합...
Maybe I'm too self-righteous.
어쩌면 나는 너무 독선적일 수도 있습니다.
His family was willing to die to hand him over to Rong Yu.
그의 가족은 그를 Rong Yu에게 넘겨주기 위해 기꺼이 죽었습니다.
They just want you to live a normal life.
그들은 단지 당신이 평범한 삶을 살기를 원합니다.
if i were your family
내가 당신의 가족이라면
I don’t want you to be a part of it either.
나는 당신도 그 일의 일부가 되는 것을 원하지 않습니다.
If you want to say no,
아니라고 말하고 싶다면,
I see.
알겠어요.
I have a burden.
부담이 있어요.
my only burden
내 유일한 짐
how much i deserve
내가 얼마나 받을 자격이 있는지
Your Majesty's trust?
폐하의 신뢰?
♫ Dusk as the sun sets♫
♫ 해가 지는 황혼♫
♫I have traveled thousands of miles ♫
♫나는 수천 마일을 여행했어요 ♫
♫ Play the sitar under the moonlight ♫
♫ 달빛 아래서 시타르를 연주해 보세요 ♫
♫ Drinks won’t let me forget ♫
♫ 술은 내가 잊지 못하게 해줄 거예요 ♫
♫I write to you about my desire♫
♫내 소망에 관해 당신에게 편지를 씁니다♫
♫Our destiny is written on paper♫
♫우리의 운명은 종이에 적혀있습니다♫
♫ Like the strongest wine ♫
♫ 가장 강한 포도주처럼 ♫
♫ There is no escape from fate ♫
♫ 운명에는 탈출구가 없습니다 ♫
♫Looking back I see you waiting♫
♫돌아보면 기다리고 있는 네가 보여♫
♫Our lives are full of joy and sadness♫
♫우리 삶은 기쁨과 슬픔 으로 가득 차 있습니다 ♫
♫ Desire crystallizes into shining stars♫
♫ 욕망은 빛나는 별들로 결정화됩니다♫
♫ You turn around silently and close the wedding book♫
♫ 당신은 조용히 돌아서서 결혼식 장부를 덮습니다♫
♫Ask how many stars there are in the sky♫
♫하늘에 별이 몇 개 있는지 물어보세요♫
♫I write to you about my desire♫
♫내 소망에 관해 당신에게 편지를 씁니다♫
♫Our destiny is written on paper♫
♫우리의 운명은 종이에 적혀있습니다♫
♫ Like the strongest wine ♫
♫ 가장 강한 포도주처럼 ♫
♫ There is no escape from fate ♫
♫ 운명에는 탈출구가 없습니다 ♫
♫Looking back I see you waiting♫
♫돌아보면 기다리고 있는 네가 보여♫
♫Our lives are full of joy and sadness♫
♫우리 삶은 기쁨과 슬픔 으로 가득 차 있습니다 ♫
♫ Desire crystallizes into shining stars♫
♫ 욕망은 빛나는 별들로 결정화됩니다♫
♫I play the sitar softly waiting for someone like you♫
♫나는 너 같은 사람을 기다리며 조용히 시타르를 연주한다 ♫
♫In the end you are my inevitable destiny♫
♫결국 당신은 나의 피할 수 없는 운명♫